HWAYOUNG CHOI

5878 Toderick Street, Vancouver, BC, V5R 4N1

Phone: 604-379-5693 | e-mail: hy3980@gmail.com | Github: https://github.com/hy2207

SUMMARY

Reliable Research Assistant pursuing degree in Information Technology. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks. Has a research experience with 2+ years of machine learning, especially, neural engineering during graduate school. Successful in contributing to peer-reviewed articles and publications exploring Neural engineering.

SKILLS

- Documentation skills: Power Point, Word, Excel, LaTeX
- Computer Language Skill: Java, Python, C#, MATLAB, PHP, JavaScript, Kotlin, Flask
- Database & Other Skill: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Git
- Basic math skills/ Analytics
- Field research

EXPERIENCE

May. 2019 to Sep. 2019	Data Analyst Intern
	Base – Vancouver, B.C
	 Building ML models to analyze personality traits using users'
	text messages using Python
Jan. 2016 to Feb. 2018	Research Assistant
	Soongsil University – Seoul, S. Korea
	 Principal investigators during research into neural engineering topics.
	 Write two papers introduced a novel neural decoding method
	 Developed algorithms that can be used by amputee patients
	by analyzing EMG signal
	 Teaching assistant of engineering math
Nov. 2012 to Dec. 2013	Teaching Assistant
	Winners academy – Seoul, S. Korea
	 Tutor secondary school students in math
EDUCATION	
Jan. 2019 to Jun. 2021	Post Baccalaureate Diploma of Emerging Technology
	Douglas College – New Westminster, B.C
Mar. 2016 to Feb. 2018	Master of Engineering
	Soongsil University – Seoul, S. Korea
	 Major in Neural Signal Processing
	 Got a scholarship given to promising students in Engineering
	Dept.
Mar. 2011 to Feb. 2016	Bachelor of Electronic Engineering

Soongsil University – Seoul, S. Korea

Research

- **Choi, H.**, You, K. J., & Shin, H. C. (2018, January). Multi-finger motion inference using M1 neural decoding. In 2018 International Conference on Information Networking (ICOIN) (pp. 18-20). IEEE.
- **Choi, H.**, You, K. J., Thakor, N. V., Schieber, M. H., & Shin, H. C. (2018). Single-Finger Neural Basis Information-Based Neural Decoder for Multi-Finger Movements. IEEE Transactions on Neural Systems and Rehabilitation Engineering, 26(12), 2240-2248.